there is some document that the Avars
есть какой-то документ что аварцы
voluntarily went to the Russian Empire and
добровольно пошли в Российскую империю и
you are the first of the Avars. Who is the
ты ты первый из аварцев Кто такое
first to say this and
говорит первый и
look, you have the Internet. Well,
посмотрите у вас же есть интернет Ну
look, you are the first. You are the first. Not a single
смотри Ты первый Ты первый ни один
Avar told me such a shame for the Avar
аварец мне такого позора для аварского
people that the Avars themselves came
народа не говорил что аварцы сами пришли
and they asked like yes there or there
и попросили типа да там или переговоры
were negotiations and they were voluntary We all know
были да и они добровольно Мы все знаем
that as a result of the Caucasian War
да что в результате Кавказской войны Да
Yes, the whole Caucasus was conquered by the Russian
ээ весь Кавказ был покорён российской
Empire you were captured you
империи вас захватили вас
were captured
захватили
Hello Hello Are you
Здравствуйте Здравствуйте Вы
from Petrozavodsk Russia
откуда Петрозаводск Россия
Karelia Yes, my dad is from
Карелия Да у меня батя из
Kondopoga and he is Russian or  Karel Or is he
Кондопоги а он русский или Карел Или он
just there in the condo in Petro, almost all of them are
просто там в кондо в Петро почти все
Ukrainians because they were sent there from Ukraine from the
украинцы потому что их из Украины из
Ukrainian Soviet Socialist
украинской Советской Социалистической
Republic and what they
Республики туда направляли а что они там
did there they worked they worked and there
делали работали работали да бумажное
was paper production. By the way, I don’t know,
производство было А кстати да я не знаю
in my opinion they closed this production there
по-моему там закрыли это производство
I remember a long time ago  I don’t know, but he was the
помню давно не знаю но он был это
chief engineer at this plant who
главным инженером на этом заводе который
makes paper because even here,
бумагу делает потому что даже вот у нас
even before the war, he even takes it pogi
когда ещ до войны он паче берёт это поги
says
говорит
piece of paper Yes And mom is Karelian And it’s clear
бумажечка Да А мама карелка А понятно
She herself and from the
Она сама и из сорта
Vali variety Vali variety Well, these are essentially Finns  the affairs of the
валы сорта валы Ну это фины по сути дела
Karelians, yes, yes, they are Finns, well, in the Soviet
карелы же да да это фины ну в Советском
Union Yes, they were called Korels, like they made the
Союзе Да их называли корелы типа сделали
Karelian-Finnish ASR, and what is your
карело-финскую АСР тако а вы кто по
nationality? I am a
национальности Я
Dagestani, there is no such nationality, there are
дагестанец нет такой национальности есть
Avars, Dargins, Kumyks, I am an Avar, many
аварцы даргинцы кумыки Я аварец многие
don’t know that Ponya, many don’t know,
не знают что Поня многие не знают
let’s say that there are Avars  Dargins are
допустим что есть аварцы даргинцы они им
easier for them Well, to speak I just even with
проще Ну говорить Я просто даже с
Russians when I communicate Yes, they don’t
россиянами когда общаюсь Да они там не
know there that there are Avars Yes, they think that
знают что есть аварцы Да они думают что
Dagestanis live in Dagestan No, well,
дагестанцы Не ну аварцев то все
practically everyone knows the Avars thanks to Khabib
практически знают благодаря хабибу
Well, also, not everyone knows that Khabib
наверное Ну тоже не все знают что Хабиб
is a Dagestani, so
есть дагестанец вот и
maybe I understand what you’re talking about here, you’re
всё может понял о чём тут общаетесь
communicating,
общаетесь
but I don’t know, I just went to Roulette
да не знаю просто зашёл в Рулетку
to chat, how do you feel about the fact that
пообщаться как относитесь к тому что
Russia is now taking uh, various small
Россия сейчас берёт ээ разные малые
nations, including Avars, Dargins,
народы в том числе аварцев даргинцев
Kumyks, Yes, from your native Dagestan and
кумыков Да с вашего родного Дагестана и
throwing them into the war in Ukraine Well,
бросает их на войну в Украину Ну мне
it seems to me  it’s not happening like it is with you,
кажется это происходит не так как у вас
I didn’t ask how it is with us as in the USA
я же не спросил как у нас как в США А
But you are an Avar Yes, you are an Avar from us they don’t
вот вы аварец Да вы аварец у нас не
take the majority from us again
берут у нас большинство ещё раз
you are an Avar How many Avars
вы аварец Сколько аварцев
are left How many Avars are left 6,000
осталось Сколько аварцев осталось 6.000
Avars at most This is the most
аварцев самое большо Это самый
numerous people in Dagestan  in
многочисленный народ в Дагестане в
Dagestan 600,000 yes or how many more than a
Дагестане 600.000 да или сколько больше
million what more than a million super
миллиона какой больше миллиона супер
more than a million Small people question uh In
больше миллиона Малый народ вопрос ээ В
what year did the Russian Empire conquer you
каком году вас покорила Российская
Well, I wouldn’t say that it
покорила Ну я бы так не сказал что нас
conquered us But what was the name of this
покорила А как как назывался этот
process when it conquered you and by Well,
процесс когда она вас завоевала и по Ну
we entered  into the composition We became a part Yes,
мы вошли в состав Мы вошли в состав Да
how did you enter as a result of which you left
как вы вошли в результате чего вы вышли
in the 10th century yes After the defeat of Imam Shamil,
в X веке да После поражения Имама Шамиля
that is, you were captured no, I don’t know us
то есть вас захватили не ну не знаю нас
I don’t think that they will capture us, well, how is it
Я не считаю что нас захвати ну как как
considered, look if the war
считается вот смотрите если война на вас
attacked you by something else  the state and you lost
напало другое государство и вы проиграли
and you became its cha Avars not all Avars
и вы стали его ча аварцы не все аварцы
not all fought against the Russian troops
не все воевали против российских войск
If you don’t know history,
тем Если вы историю не знаете е у вас
look you had your own state But there
смотрите у вас было своё государство Да
wasn’t a state as such
вот государства то как такового не было
Well, it wasn’t Wait, it was
Ну как не было Подождите было
Political power  if it weren’t on the
Политическая власть бы ну как не было на
territory and there was a Kumyk state
территории и кумыкское государство было
and the Avars had their own state, there
и у аварцев было своё государство
wasn’t a Kumyk state either, you
кумыкское государство тоже не было вы
at least read the history Now I’ll
историю хотя бы читали Сейчас я вам
tell you now I’ll tell you Now I’ll tell you straight
сейчас я вам скажу Сейчас я вам прямо
let’s go
скажу давайте давайте
here Tuli Tulin Khanate Yes, for example, that’s
вот Тули тулинское ханство Да например
how the Kumyk was  a state
так было кумыкское государственное
formation that existed from the 10th to the 10th
образование существовавшее с X по X
centuries on the territory And so on,
веках на территории Вот и так дальше то
that is, there were Kumyks who fought, don’t
есть были вот кумыки воевали не
wait, I’m not saying that they were on the
подождите не я говорю что были на
territory Yes, there were
территории Да Кавказа были
state formations in the Caucasus Yes,
государственные образования Да были на
you were attacked by the Russian Empire and
вас на вас напала Российская империя и
captured you or not captured  what
захватила вас так или не захватила как
is the name of this process,
называется это проце
everything is right, look at you
обя пра всё правильно вот смотрите вас
Avars Yes, you lived like wild tribes or
аварцев Да вы жили как дикие племена или
you had some kind of political
у вас было какое-то политическое
formation then the Avars, some of the
образование тогда вот аварцы часть
Avars did not fight with the Russian super, some did not
аварцев не воевала с российской супер
fight during the Second World
часть не воевала во время Второй мировой
War, some of the Russians did not fight with
войны часть русских не воевала с
Hitler What kind of Imam Shamil
Гитлером Какая ли во Имама Шамиля
Tell me, tell me how the Avars became part of the
Скажите скажите как авар стали частью
Russian Empire
Российской империи
Yes, I don’t remember In what year, as
Да был по я не помню В каком году в
a result of which you left as a result of
результате чего вы вышли в результате
nothing, we are just part of the Avars By the way,
ничего мы просто часть аварцев Кстати
before all this, she was, well, in the sense of being
до всего вот этого она была ну в смысле
part of the Russian Empire, yes  once again, as
в части российской империи да ещё раз в
a result of nothing, you ended up in the Russian
результате ничего вы попали в Российскую
Empire, you said as a result of nothing,
империю вы сказали в результате ничего
or after all, as a result of defeat in
или всё-таки в результате поражения в
the war, you became part of the Russian Empire, before that we were
войне вы стали частью Российской империи
practically already part of a
мы до этого уже практически были в части
part of a part of the empire state, we were
в составе части империи стате мы были
some kind of part of the empire A  how did you How did you
какой-то ча империи А как вы Как вы
become this part of the Russian Empire with
стали этой частью Российской империи с
Ivan Shamil, by the way, was with these
вот Иван Шамиль кстати был с этими
now how did you in general, how did you first
сейчас как вы вообще вот как вы впервые
become and in what year did you become part of the
стали и в каком году стали частью
Russian Empire in the 10th century we became
Российской империи в X веке мы стали как
how did you become the Avars came to bow to the
как вы стали пришли аварцы на поклон
Tsar Accept us  to the Russian Empire or
царю Прими нас на Российскую империю или
how nothing, well, they didn’t come to bow to the Tsar,
как ничего не ну на поклон к царю не
but there were negotiators,
приходили но были переговорщики
as far as I remember then, from Pyatigorsk or
насколько я помню тогда с Пятигорска или
from somewhere they came, negotiators,
откуда-то они приехали переговорщики да
and we became part of the Russian Empire,
и мы вошли в состав Российской империи
and on the basis of what, on the basis of the fact
да на основании чего на основании того
that we wanted to become part  empires Who are
что мы хотели стать частью империи Кто
we stop stop look And with whom were you
мы стоп стоп смотрите А с кем были вы
saying that you didn’t have a state and
сказали что у вас не было государства а
now you say that some
теперь говорите что приехали какие-то
negotiators arrived And with whom did they
переговорщики А с кем они
negotiate if you
переговаривались если у вас государства
didn’t have a state they negotiated with the
не было они переговаривались со
elders, that is,
старейшинами то есть государственно
you had a state political formation  yes,
политическое образование было у вас так
but it was not the same as in the
но оно было не такое вот как в
modern concept. That is, there were
современном понятии То есть были
elders and they ruled. Well, let’s say
старейшины да они управляли А ну скажем
so, large settlements. Well,
так крупными населёнными пунктами Ну
large settlements
крупными селениями
or some of them became part of the
иле п и они часть вошла в состав
then empire; some did not agree and did
тогдашней империи часть не согласилась и
not want to tell you. I’m
не захотела можете сказать Мне вот
interested in  on the basis of what treaty
интересно на основании какого договора
did you then voluntarily enter the Russian
вы вошли тогда добровольно в Российскую
Empire? I don’t even remember there was some kind of treaty.
империю я даже не помню какой-то договор
Well, this is the history of your people, well,
был Ну это же история вашего народа ну
really. Well, yes, you voluntarily entered there.
реально Ну да вы добровольно туда вошли
Well, it’s cool and you don’t know when they
Ну да прикольно и не знаете когда вот
taught you at school, look, we’re an avar
вам в школе учили смотрите мы авар
like this-  then in such and such a year they signed there,
такого-то в таком-то году подписали там
for example, the Minsk agreements on joining the
например минские соглашения о вхождении
Russian Empire, for example,
в Российскую империю например подписали
you signed the Minsk agreements there. Well, I’m
это вы там минские соглашения Ну я тебе
telling you, tell me, there is some document
говорю скажи нано есть какой-то документ
that the Avars voluntarily went to the
что аварцы добровольно пошли в
Russian Empire, you are the first of the
Российскую империю ты ты первый из
Avars, who says this first  and
аварцев Кто такое говорит первый и
look, you have the Internet. Well,
посмотрите у вас же есть интернет Ну
look, you are the first. You are the first. Not the only
смотри Ты первый Ты первый не один
Avar told me such a shame for the Avar
аварец мне такого позора для аварского
people that the Avars themselves came
народа не говорил что аварцы сами пришли
and asked for it. Yes, there were negotiations, yes, or
и попросили ти Да там или переговоры
voluntarily. We all know
были да ини добровольно Мы все знаем да
that as a result of the Caucasian War.
что в результате Кавказской войны
Yes, all  The Caucasus was conquered by the Russian
Да весь Кавказ был покорён Российской
Empire you were captured you were captured you
империей вас захватили вас захватили вы
became
стали
what you became subjects of the Russian
че вы стали подданными Российской
Empire Yes your your grandfathers grandmothers
империи Да ваши ваших дедушек бабушек
Yermolov's Soldiers were
ермоловские Солдаты было бабушка и
grandparents my hundred empires have not yet lived
дедушка мои ста империи ещё не жили ещё
again this is figuratively grandparents You
раз это образно бабушки и дедушки Вы
know yes that is Yermolov's Soldiers of
знаете да то есть ермоловские Солдаты
your pregnant  grandfathers Yes, in huge
ваших беременных дедушек Да в огромных
quantities, here you are, by the way,
количествах вот Вас кстати вот кстати и
by the way, and you are now looking at you, shamefully yes We
смотрите и вы сейчас вы позорно да Мы
know how Russia Russian troops slaughtered
знаем как Росси русские войска вырезали
entire villages, slaughtered Avars, slaughtered
целые аулы вырезали с аварца вырезали
let's say we were so
давайте мы была такая
double, we'll see with you now the
двойная мы сейчас с вами
sound is gone, the sound is gone Yes And
посмотрим пропал звук пропал Да И вот
that's the most interesting thing  Yes, the sound disappeared. It
что самое интересное да звук пропал
seems that yes, but I’m saying that the Zaporozhye
Вроде бы да а я говорю что запорожские
Cossacks who had whom,
казаки которые имели которых
look, I’m discovering like the genocide of the
смотрите вот открываю типа геноцид
Avars with a yoke and
аварцев ярмом и
ho-ho, that’s what Yermolov writes in the Caucasus, the
хо-хо так и пишет Ермолов на Кавказе
rest is a Moscow Komsomol member, even your
оста это Московский комсомолец даже ваша
Russian writes this
Российская это пишет
Yes, look at how they write about Yermolov
Да так о смотрите как про Ермолова пишут
Yes  your
Да ваши
Dagestan imprisoned their women, let them
Дагестан сажал их женщин пускал вот так
talk about him like this, Military
про него говорят вот Военное
Review Russian website writes yes, the outstanding
обозрение русский сайт пишет да выдающий
Russian commander, the genocide against the
русский полководец геноцид в отношении
Circassians and other peoples of the North
черкесова и прочих народов Северного
Caucasus is justified,
Кавказа оправдывается оказывает
resists And so on, that is,
сопротивление И так дальше то есть
look at the Ukrainians, hold the Russians, the
смотрите украинцев подержи русские
Russians are mocking your ancestors,
русские издеваются над вашими предками
saying handsome yes  he will join with fire and sword
говоря красавчик да он Огнём и мечом
Yes and now you are obedient not only
присоединятся Да и сейчас вы покорно не
obedient You say that they are bad And
то что покорно Говорите Что они плохие А
you justify them you could If you you
вы их оправдываете вы могли Если вы вы
could just remain silent lower your eyes
могли просто промолчать опустить глаза
lower your eyes and tell me I can’t tell you
опустить глаза и сказать я не могу тебе
Good fellow from Ukraine answer I’m
Добрый молодец из Украины ответить мне
ashamed but I don’t care  I can’t because I
стыдно но я ничего не могу потому что я
live in a country in which I
живу в стране в которой я
and My people say we have turned from once proud
и Мой народ скажи мы из гордых когда-то
mountaineers
горцев превратились
into some kind of
в каких-то
mountain people
горных просто
who simply cannot stand up for themselves we yes
которые не могут за себя постоять мы да
yes tell us too The Kremlin shepherd is grazing
да скажи и нас Кремлёвский пастух выпаса
grazing and you are ashamed  you understand,
ет выпаса ет и тебе стыдно понимаешь ты
that’s why it’s Podgora Because you
ж поэтому поэтому подгора Потому что ты
know, you know in
знаешь ты знаеш в
what condition your Dagestan lives, you
каком состоянии живёт твой Дагестан ты
’ve seen and how the Russians treat you as
видел и как русские относятся к вам как
people Yes, they came and came in large numbers And
людям Да приехали что-то там понаехали И
so on That’s how it licks the Americans Well,
так дальше Вот так американцам лижет Ну
what happens is that the most
что оно же получается что самое
interesting thing is  Moscow opened his mouth about the
интересное Москвы открыл рот про
Americans Tell me about the Americans
американцев Расскажи мне про американцев
Moscow is its territory Accept all
Москва територию свою Прим все
political scientists are already the nation itself yes this is oh yes
политологи уже самая нация да это ой да
I have those you know look at the number from the
у меня такие знаешь смотри номер из
Kursk region Tell me how how Russia
Курской области Расскажи как как Россия
Yes, it allowed that the NATO Americans
Да вот допустила что американцы натовцы
took the Kursk region from it Let
отобрали у неё курскую область Давай у
us have this  Of course, you have savagery. And we have
нас это у вас конечно дикость А у нас
Ukrainian license plates, please, freely.
украинские номера пожалуйста свободно
This is the case with us too. You see, temporarily in the
Это так и у нас вот да Видите временно в
city of Sudzha. Yes, the re-registration of
городе Суджа Да уже идёт перерегистрация
plates to normal ones is already underway with normal ones.
номеров на нормальный с нормальными фж
there is a problem who
самая большая проблема есть которые
understand that they are angry, they are waiting for
понимают что они их это злит они Ждут
the moment to throw off their chains Yes, to
момента чтобы скинуть свои цепи Да чтобы
raise an Uprising like the uprising of
поднять Восстание как вот восстание
Spartacus Yes, they were because they were
Спартака Да они были потому что их
captured once Yes, and they did it, but they
захватили когда-то Да и сделали но у них
had the spirit, they did the Uprising Yes, someone
был дух они сделали Восстание Да кто-то
died  someone doesn’t, but
погиб кто-то нет но
they didn’t live in the soul. And there are people
они не жили в душе А есть люди вот такие
like you who are already in the soul. Yes, you are already in the
как ты который в душе уже Да ты уже в
soul, and moreover, you will
душе и больше того ты своим детям будешь
poison the lives of your children and you tell them. We we
отравлять жизнь и ты им рассказывать Мы
gave birth to we you we were born into must
мы родили мы ты мы родились в должны
live this  this is how nature is built, it’s
жить это так так природа построена
true, yes, we won’t change anything, it’s
правда да мы ничего не изменим это всё
all the will of the Almighty,
на всю воля Всевышнего сделала у нас
our ancestors lost the war to the Russian
наши предки проиграли войну Российской
Empire and everything is like this. Why did the Ukrainians
империи и всё вот так Почему украинцы Да
jump out of this Russian Empire? Yes,
выскочили из этой Российской империи
they jumped out 100 years ago now.
дали им было 100 лет назад сейчас Да
Why did Latvia Lithuania Estonia jump out?  from
почему Латвия Литва Эстония выскочила из
this Russian Empire Finland
этой Российской империи Финляндия
jumped out Yes Poland jumped out all the proud
выскочила Да Польша выскочила все гордые
peoples Yes who were deprived of their
народы Да которые были лишились своей
statehood
государственности
they
они годами
carried the Ray of struggle for years they
несли Луч борьбы они
persecuted poets, national figures, musicians Yes they
музыканты преследовали Да
shot and tortured them in prisons but they
расстреливали замучили в тюрмах но они
carried this taste of Freedom And if we
несли этот вкус Свободы И если мы
look at Ukraine Yes Ukraine in  At the beginning of the 20th
посмотрим Украину Да Украина в начале XX
century, the Soviet
века проиграла Советскому вот
government lost its war for independence to the Russian government
правительству российскому войну за
and Russia
независимость свою и Россия захватила
then captured it again, yes, a huge number of
тогда её снова да огромное количество
Ukrainians fought in the Ukrainian
украинцев боролось в украинской
rebel army, then there
повстанское армии потом огромное
were a huge number of partisans, Yes, there were a
количество в партизанах было Да
lot of anti-Soviet
антисоветских очень много было
dissidents, how many Yes, and even at the end of the
диссидентов сколько Да и даже в конце
Soviet Union, Ukrainian figures like
Советского Союза украинских деятелей как
Here is Vasyl Stus
вот Василя стуса
Yes, they were tortured in prisons and the
Да пытали в тюрьмах и
trumpet came off there, they made it for him and we became
там оторвался тромп делали им и мы стали
independent in 1990, but even though in
независимы в де году да хотя е В
1995, no one
девяносто там пятом шестом никто даже и
could even imagine that there would be
не мог представить что вот будет
independence. But the people were not people, people
независимость Но люди люди не были люди
wore embroidered shirts, people wrote Ukrainian
одевали вышиванку люди писали украинские
poetry.  people
стихи люди
took the works of the kobzar Taras Shevchenko
брали сочинения кобзаря Тараса Шевченко
Yes, and they went out and read,
Да и выходили читали делали
did Shevchenko readings, did what they
шевченковские читания делали то что
could, did what they couldn’t, yes,
можно было делали то что нельзя было да
my father received Ukrainian embroidery for
у меня отца за украинскую вышивку за то
coming to the university, and he was
что он в университет пришёл да его
called to the dean’s office. Yes, he went to desk
вызывали в декана Да его на парт
meetings like these  they drove
собрания типа вот эти гоняли
Komsomol members there or that something
комсомольские там или что что-то в
was sent to university because he and
университетские было за то что он и
many, many people, my father and mother
много-много людей у меня отец и мать
came out in ninety-eighty-
выходили девяностый восемьдесят девятый
nine with Ukrainian flags as part of the uh
год с украинскими флагами в составе ээ
Rukh for the independence of Ukraine And even
Руха вот за независимость Украины Да и
now and now I’m proud of them because  that
сейчас и сейчас я горжусь ими потому что
they I was little then, I didn’t understand,
они я тогда был маленький я не понимал
but all this was for me Well, let’s
да всего этого для меня это было Ну вот
go to my brother with such flags Yes,
пошли на брат с флагами такими Да
Ukrainian ones. I didn’t understand all the
украинскими вот Я не понимал всей
depth now that I’m an adult, I
глубины сейчас когда я взрослый я
understand how lucky I am with my
понимаю насколько мне повезло э с
parents that I can be proud of them Yes  I,
родителями что я могу ими гордиться Да я
uh, see that they were an Example for me,
ээ вижу что они были Примером для меня
they were an Example for me, but you are not an
они были Примером для меня а ты не есть
Example for your children. Yes, your children
Примером для своих детей Да твои дети
understand how much you are afraid of
понимают насколько ты ты ж боишься
the boss, you are afraid of the mayor, you are afraid of the
начальника ты боишься мэра ты боишься
president, you are afraid of everyone, and you are in
президента ты всех боишься да и ты в
your children.
своих детях
Raised by my parents.  a huge
Воспитываю мои родители огромнейшее им
thank you to them for raising me to be an intelligent
Спасибо что они воспитали меня умным
person and a free person, this is a thing
человеком и свободным человеком это вещь
that you can’t just pick up and buy in a
которую нельзя просто взять и купить в
store, you can’t come and say
магазине ты не можешь прийти и сказать
Give me a feeling of Freedom Give
Дайте мне ощущение Свободы Дайте мне
me dignity Yes give me honor
достоинство Да дайте мне честь не
this is not for sale You either grew up with it Yes
продаётся такое ты либо с этим вырос Да
you either  I felt something or
ты либо ощутил себе-то либо ничего у
you don’t have any of this And you You envy me
тебя этого нет И ты Ты завидуешь мне
because you see that a
потому что ты видишь что перед тобой
free person is sitting in front of you and you can’t,
сидит свободный человек а ты не можешь
nothing bothers you You know how this
ничего тебя коробит Знаешь как вот
person is jealous of the one who
человек который он завидует тому У кого
has a car, he says And this is his
есть машина он говорит А это у него
connection He stole and so on
связь Он наворовал и так дальше вместо
instead of going to work and here you are,
того чтобы пойти на работу так и тут ты
instead of awakening the spirit in your
вместо того чтобы пробудить дух в своём
heart and admitting to yourself that Yes, I
сердце да признаться себе что Да я сла
was weak and that’s all, but I don’t want My children to
был да и всё но я не хочу чтобы Мои дети
live like this, yes you are already living out your life
Так жили да ты уже доживает свою жизнь
You just lived it in the Soviet Union in the
Ты просто прожил её в Советском Союзе в
Russian Federation and your children
Российской Федерации и твои дети сейчас
live now Yes, but at least you had this
живут Да но у тебя хотя бы был вот этот
Light Yes, and you wouldn’t be afraid and
Огонёк Да и ты бы не побоялся и
try to convey the spirit of Freedom to your children
попробовал бы передать детям дух Свободы
This is the biggest asset Let’s turn it on
Это самый огромный актив Давай включайте
and you didn’t usually like to work  you were persecuted by the
и работать же не любили обычно вас гнали
damn Poles oak in full,
блин поляки дуба по полной программе
you got something,
что-нибудь получилось у вас
but you got something
б а получилось у тебя что-нибудь
Yes, by the way, the Avars spot Well, not only from the
Да кстати аварцев спота Ну не только от
Avars Well, from the whole
аварцев Ну от всего Дагестана
collective Dagestan, you got the program, you were
коллективного вы схлопотал программе вас
only driven there so much And what do you have with
только столько там гоняли А что у тебя с
these  Have you started having nervous
этими У тебя что эти Начались да нервные
tics or something? Tell me about the Avars and
тики что ли Расскажи про аварцев и
Dagestan, I’m
Дагестан мне
interested in the
интересно у ниб
fact that they have their own state. We carried it
свобо есть своё государство Мы пронесли
through centuries of millennia, we got
через столетия тысячелетий мы получили
our own state, we achieved it. Yes, we
своё государство мы добились Да мы
now live in an independent country, what
сейчас живём в независимой стране что у
can’t you do there, we live in  in our
вас там не получается мы живём в своей
country Yes, in our own country we elect a
стране Да мы в своей стране мы выбираем
president for ourselves because we want
себе президента так как мы хотим
deputies just like you want And you are
депутатов так как вы хотим А вы
conquered and you envy us I see it
покорённый и Ты завидуешь нам я вижу это
in your eyes I see everything is completely in
по твоим глазам вижу всё вот полностью в
ruins Where is your industry there is none
труху Где ваша промышленность нету её
Industry that you produce what you
Промышленности что вы производите чего
don’t  you even produce your own grain,
не производите вы даже зерно своё уже
you’ve already stopped producing you,
перестали производить вам вы уже никому
no one needs you anymore You know, Wait Stop Our
не нужны А знаете Подожди Стоп У нас
grain has stopped growing, you’ve
перестало расти зерно вы ничего
collected practically nothing from the harvest,
практически из урожая ничего не собрали
and in fact, even before, you at least
и вы по сути дела даже раньше Вы хоть
paid with grain And now you
зерном расплачивались А сейчас у вас
don’t even have that with  you are paying And
даже этого нету чем вы расплачивается А
for Why why didn’t we collect the harvest
по Почему почему мы не собрали урожай
with which you transported
которыми на которых вы перевозили это
all this, in short, he turned off the sound, come on,
всё он короче отключил звук давай всё
dude, you’re going, just
чувак ты идёшь просто
let’s write to my Telegram right away, the
давай пись на мий Telegram прям зараз
VN axis and
ось ВН а
Popik is more and more respectful YouTube
Попик це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube
keeping us busy through the skarg Orcs in  your ban and
заня нас через скарг Орки в твый бан и
so much video I don’t show people
дуже багато видео не показую людям
often don’t show information about streams
вчасно не показуе информация про стримы
for this purpose we Mali operational
тому для того щб мы Мали оперативный
link to write right away and popik
звязок пишиться прямо зараз а попик
there in telegram okrim video shchezh
там в телеграми окрим видео ще теж
Tsikava and Korisna information and we are guilty
цикава и корисна информация и мы повинни
of you trimati postiyny operational
з вами тримати постийний оперативный
link
звязок
independent in  I'll show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine
YouTube Слава Украине
write Ja
пиши Ja